对任何机器人来说，一个非常重要的考虑因素是所有可能的点
A really important consideration with any robot is the set of all possible points that
它可以到达。
it can reach.
我们将此卷称为机器人的工作空间。
And we refer to this volume as the workspace of the robot.
对于机器人随附的数据表中的大多数工业机器人手臂，您可以
For most industrial robot arms in the data sheet that comes with the robot, you could
找到看起来像这样的图表。
find the diagram that looks something like this.
它是机器人的平面图和侧视图。
It is a plain view and side elevation view of the robot.
你在这里看到的标有蓝色的是机器人可达到的体积。
And what you can see here marked in blue is the reachable volume of the robot.
我们可以看到这个体积在机器人身体周围也无法到达。
We can see that this volume around the body of the robot where it cannot reach either.
这是由于特定关节或其运动范围的机械限制
And this is due to mechanical limits on the range of motion of particular joints or it’s
机器人控制软件的神器，以防止手臂的部分相交或
an artifact of the robot control software to prevent parts of the arm intersecting or
与机器人手臂或其基座的其他部分碰撞。
colliding with other parts of the robot's arm or its base.